<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>two-cents on unAssuming</title>
    <link>https://www.unassuming.page/tags/two-cents/</link>
    <description>Recent content in two-cents on unAssuming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.unassuming.page/tags/two-cents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Proof Assistants for Typesetting Maths</title>
      <link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/mathematics/proof_asssistants_for_typesetting_maths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/mathematics/proof_asssistants_for_typesetting_maths/</guid>
      <description>I am currently trying make our exercise sheets HTML based to allow for things like drop down solutions, which start in a collapsed state. I ended up asking myself whether it might be possible yet to verify proofs submitted by students automatically. So I looked for Proof Assistants and ended up with lean. In particular I tried out the Natural Numbers Game and started reading Theorem Proving in Lean for a more comprehensive introduction.
Landmark based Maths vs Steps in Proof Assistants The first contrast I noticed was the following. When you write down Maths for another human, you tend to write something like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Quotas</title>
      <link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/smart-quota/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/smart-quota/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While equal rights could be viewed as an issue of the past (at least in most
developed countries), equal opportunity is still an open issue. In a free
market wages and hiring decisions are not up to the law and thus equal rights
are not enough to guarantee equal opportunity. While wages for equal work can
be achieved with transparency and public pressure, it is much more difficult to
quantify hiring discrimination. For this reason many people argue for a quota
to actually affect these decisions with written law, so that injustices could
be tried in court.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Recipe for Endless War</title>
      <link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/recipe_for_endless_war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/recipe_for_endless_war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On sunday the game of the &amp;ldquo;Hooligan Eagles&amp;rdquo; against the &amp;ldquo;LesserEvil Hawks&amp;rdquo;
is taking place. The city decided, in order to protect the police, it
will not send in police to enforce a peaceful game. Instead, it intends to
supply the fans of the &amp;ldquo;LesserEvil Hawks&amp;rdquo; with handguns so they can protect
themselves against the often violent fans of the &amp;ldquo;Hooligan Eagles&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the referee takes one of the Hooligan Eagles players off the field for a
foul, the camera pans to an increasingly rowdy crowd of Eagle fans close to
the Hawks fan section.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Education System</title>
      <link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/better_education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/better_education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Education is one of those topics, which everyone has an opinion on, and reforms
are proposed every other day. In Germany it is even worse, as education is state&amp;rsquo;s
jurisdiction, so multiply the mess by 16. So, is this just another
proposal which claims to be much better than any others proposed before?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are only two colors</title>
      <link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/there-are-only-two-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/there-are-only-two-colors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;a lot of people would protest. There are of course more than two colors. For
example &amp;ldquo;red, green, blue&amp;rdquo; are already three. Okay so maybe the statement was
an exaggeration. How about &amp;ldquo;only 5 colors&amp;rdquo; (Red, Yellow, Green, Blue,
Violet)? Some people might start to agree with that statement. Other people
might list a few more. At some point words for more colors will run out. Yet
some people would still disagree with the statement: &amp;ldquo;there are only x
colors&amp;rdquo;. Even though we only have a finite number of words for them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concise Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/concise_philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/concise_philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is&#34;&gt;What is?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think, therefore I am - &lt;em&gt;Descartes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can be sure that something exists which does the thinking. You might
now argue that abstract things like language and mathematics exist. Since a
version of them can be part of your consciousness, which exists. But beyond
that nothing concrete needs to exist, as thought experiments like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brain_in_a_vat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Brain in a
vat&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Boltzmann
Brains&lt;/a&gt;
prove (as they are not falsifiable you can not prove you are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; one
of those, so therefore you can not prove that anything concrete &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; exist).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
