<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on unAssuming</title>
    <link>https://www.unassuming.page/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on unAssuming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.unassuming.page/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Version Control with Git</title>
      <link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/programming/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/programming/git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When choosing a programming language or database, there are so many options to
choose from. And people regularly create new options since they are not happy
with the existing ones. But for version control, there exists essentially just
one option: &lt;code&gt;Git&lt;/code&gt;. And while it takes some getting used to, it must do something
right, if nobody wants to spend the effort to improve upon it. This is a
small introduction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming in Lean</title>
      <link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/programming/programming-in-lean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/programming/programming-in-lean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lean is quite a bit different from other programming languages. People familiar
with Haskell (or other functional programming languages) might be a bit more
comfortable  from the get go, but if you do not have that background there are
a couple of stumbling blocks you might encounter. So I thought I would point
out some of the gotchas I sumbled over learning this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intuitive Indexing</title>
      <link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/programming/intuitive-indexing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/programming/intuitive-indexing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While most programming languages use 0-based indexing &lt;a href=&#34;https://hisham.hm/2021/01/18/again-on-0-based-vs-1-based-indexing/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;some people are not
convinced&lt;/a&gt; that this is a good thing and not just the legacy of
the language C. They argue that starting to index with one is more &lt;em&gt;intuitive&lt;/em&gt;
than starting to index with zero, and that there is no good reason to use
0-based indices besides pointer arithmetic which should not be of concern to
higher level programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to be fair, proponents of zero based indexing have mostly failed to provide
a convincing argument for their preference (&lt;a href=&#34;#5-ranges&#34;&gt;Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s range
argument&lt;/a&gt; aside). To remedy this, I am going to present 5 arguments
for 0-based indexing and address the intuition argument of 1-based
indexing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Of</title>
      <link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/programming/making-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 18:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/programming/making-of/</guid>
      <description>Hugo I used Hugo (alternatives: jekyll, gatsby) to generate a static site from markdown pages.
Theme I use the fuji theme for styling
Github Pages You can publish to the gh_pages branch using Github actions. The website is then served by Github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
