<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>two-cents on Felix' Blog</title><link>https://felixbenning.github.io/tags/two-cents/</link><description>Recent content in two-cents on Felix' Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://felixbenning.github.io/tags/two-cents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Better Education System</title><link>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/two-cents/better_education/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/two-cents/better_education/</guid><description>&lt;p>Education is one of those topics, which everyone has an opinion on, and reforms
are proposed every other day. In Germany it is even worse, as education is state&amp;rsquo;s
jurisdiction, so multiply the mess by 16. So, is this just another
proposal which claims to be much better than any others proposed before?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>There are only two colors</title><link>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/two-cents/there-are-only-two-colors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/two-cents/there-are-only-two-colors/</guid><description>&lt;p>a lot of people would protest. There are of course more than two colors. For
example &amp;ldquo;red, green, blue&amp;rdquo; are already three. Okay so maybe the statement was
an exaggeration. How about &amp;ldquo;only 5 colors&amp;rdquo; (Red, Yellow, Green, Blue,
Violet)? Some people might start to agree with that statement. Other people
might list a few more. At some point words for more colors will run out. Yet
some people would still disagree with the statement: &amp;ldquo;there are only x
colors&amp;rdquo;. Even though we only have a finite number of words for them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Concise Philosophy</title><link>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/two-cents/concise_philosopy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/two-cents/concise_philosopy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Before we begin, I should note that certain things simply seem impossible.
You can not reason whether logic makes sense using logic. So I will not even
try. We will see shortly that I find some other things to be impossible.
Being trained in mathematics, I do not find that too unusual. While I think
that my belief system turns out to be remarkable consistent and did not
really encounter any problems in the last few years, I would be stupid to
think I have discovered an absolute truth. But since the contrary is
grammatically unwieldy, I will present my thoughts as such.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>