<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>politics on unAssuming</title><link>https://www.unassuming.page/tags/politics/</link><description>Recent content in politics on unAssuming</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.unassuming.page/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Disease Spreads Exponentially</title><link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/mathematics/why-disease-spreads-exponentially/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/mathematics/why-disease-spreads-exponentially/</guid><description>&lt;p>If there is one thing this pandemic has taught us, then it is that few people
truly understand exponential growth. This post is an attempt to explore this
magical function with minimal prerequisites.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smart Quotas</title><link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/smart-quota/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/smart-quota/</guid><description>&lt;p>While equal rights could be viewed as an issue of the past (at least in most
developed countries), equal opportunity is still an open issue. In a free
market wages and hiring decisions are not up to the law and thus equal rights
are not enough to guarantee equal opportunity. While wages for equal work can
be achieved with transparency and public pressure, it is much more difficult to
quantify hiring discrimination. For this reason many people argue for a quota
to actually affect these decisions with written law, so that injustices could
be tried in court.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Recipe for Endless War</title><link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/recipe_for_endless_war/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/recipe_for_endless_war/</guid><description>&lt;p>On sunday the game of the &amp;ldquo;Hooligan Eagles&amp;rdquo; against the &amp;ldquo;LesserEvil Hawks&amp;rdquo;
is taking place. The city decided, in order to protect the police, it
will not send in police to enforce a peaceful game. Instead, it intends to
supply the fans of the &amp;ldquo;LesserEvil Hawks&amp;rdquo; with handguns so they can protect
themselves against the often violent fans of the &amp;ldquo;Hooligan Eagles&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the referee takes one of the Hooligan Eagles players off the field for a
foul, the camera pans to an increasingly rowdy crowd of Eagle fans close to
the Hawks fan section.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CO2 Budget Model</title><link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/economics/co2_budget_model/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/economics/co2_budget_model/</guid><description> This is a quick and dirty embedding of an older shiny app you can also access in full size</description></item><item><title>The Economic Impact of Climate Neutrality</title><link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/economics/econ_impact_of_carbon_neutrality/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/economics/econ_impact_of_carbon_neutrality/</guid><description>&lt;p>How much does it cost to become Carbon Neutral? Is it feasible? Or is it too
radical? I think that many people paint a grimmer picture than necessary. In
fact I would go so far as to say we can solve climate change in our lunch
break. Let me explain&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Better Education System</title><link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/better_education/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/better_education/</guid><description>&lt;p>Education is one of those topics, which everyone has an opinion on, and reforms
are proposed every other day. In Germany it is even worse, as education is state&amp;rsquo;s
jurisdiction, so multiply the mess by 16. So, is this just another
proposal which claims to be much better than any others proposed before?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>There are only two colors</title><link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/there-are-only-two-colors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/two-cents/there-are-only-two-colors/</guid><description>&lt;p>a lot of people would protest. There are of course more than two colors. For
example &amp;ldquo;red, green, blue&amp;rdquo; are already three. Okay so maybe the statement was
an exaggeration. How about &amp;ldquo;only 5 colors&amp;rdquo; (Red, Yellow, Green, Blue,
Violet)? Some people might start to agree with that statement. Other people
might list a few more. At some point words for more colors will run out. Yet
some people would still disagree with the statement: &amp;ldquo;there are only x
colors&amp;rdquo;. Even though we only have a finite number of words for them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Communism is not discussed in Economics</title><link>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/economics/communism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.unassuming.page/blog/economics/communism/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Communism is not a bad economic system. It is not an economic system.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Every economic system is fundamentally an allocation algorithm. Somehow it
must be decided what is produced, and who can use/consume that. An economic
system is the “recipe” (algorithm) for making this decision. If you specify
such an algorithm, you can make statements about the result.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>