<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Felix' Blog</title><link>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Felix' Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Economic Impact of Climate Neutrality</title><link>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/economics/econ_impact_of_carbon_neutrality/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/economics/econ_impact_of_carbon_neutrality/</guid><description>&lt;p>How much does it cost to become Carbon Neutral? Is it feasible? Or is it too
radical? I think that many people paint a grimmer picture than necessary. In
fact I would go so far as to say we can solve climate change in our lunch
break. Let me explain&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Better Education System</title><link>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/two-cents/better_education/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/two-cents/better_education/</guid><description>&lt;p>Education is one of those topics, which everyone has an opinion on, and reforms
are proposed every other day. In Germany it is even worse, as education is state&amp;rsquo;s
jurisdiction, so multiply the mess by 16. So, is this just another
proposal which claims to be much better than any others proposed before?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Certificates are the Right Tool for Limiting CO2 Emission</title><link>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/economics/why_certificates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/economics/why_certificates/</guid><description>&lt;p>First of all: A tax and certificate system is equivalent to some degree. The
main difference is that taxes set prices while certificates set quantities.
But more on that later. And since taxes are easier to understand I will start
with explaining them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>There are only two colors</title><link>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/two-cents/there-are-only-two-colors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/two-cents/there-are-only-two-colors/</guid><description>&lt;p>a lot of people would protest. There are of course more than two colors. For
example &amp;ldquo;red, green, blue&amp;rdquo; are already three. Okay so maybe the statement was
an exaggeration. How about &amp;ldquo;only 5 colors&amp;rdquo; (Red, Yellow, Green, Blue,
Violet)? Some people might start to agree with that statement. Other people
might list a few more. At some point words for more colors will run out. Yet
some people would still disagree with the statement: &amp;ldquo;there are only x
colors&amp;rdquo;. Even though we only have a finite number of words for them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Communism is not discussed in Economics</title><link>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/economics/communism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/economics/communism/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Communism is not a bad economic system. It is not an economic system.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Every economic system is fundamentally an allocation algorithm. Somehow it
must be decided what is produced, and who can use/consume that. An economic
system is the “recipe” (algorithm) for making this decision. If you specify
such an algorithm, you can make statements about the result.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Concise Philosophy</title><link>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/two-cents/concise_philosopy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/two-cents/concise_philosopy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Before we begin, I should note that certain things simply seem impossible.
You can not reason whether logic makes sense using logic. So I will not even
try. We will see shortly that I find some other things to be impossible.
Being trained in mathematics, I do not find that too unusual. While I think
that my belief system turns out to be remarkable consistent and did not
really encounter any problems in the last few years, I would be stupid to
think I have discovered an absolute truth. But since the contrary is
grammatically unwieldy, I will present my thoughts as such.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zero vs One-based Indexing</title><link>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/programming/0_vs_1_based_indexing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://felixbenning.github.io/blog/programming/0_vs_1_based_indexing/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="it-is-only-about-pointers">&amp;ldquo;It is only about pointers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Proponents of counting from 1 often think that this is about pointers and
claim that it only makes sense for computer scientist as accessing an element
from an array on hardware translates to addition to the pointer which means
that the first element is at 0. They then like to argue that an index from 1
would make more sense in maths and &amp;ldquo;for counting&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will try to explain why this is not the case.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>